A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Foundation
  - Rockefeller Foundation - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Resignation, April 1940, 1940, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 348)
    "Remarks of the Retiring Chairman Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at the Meeting of the Rockefeller Foundation, April 3, 1940."
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 349)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, January-October 1940 (Box 34, Folder 350)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
    30.3C
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, November-December 1940 (Box 35, Folder 351)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1941-1942 (Box 35, Folder 352)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman, Jerome D. Greene, Karl T. Compton, John Foster Dulles.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 353)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1947-1948 (Box 35, Folder 354)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, February-August 1949 (Box 35, Folder 355)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, September-December 1949 (Box 35, Folder 356)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, J. Douglas Brown, Joseph H. Willits, Anna M. Rosenberg.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 357)
    Lists of trustees with retirement dates. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 358)
    Names proposed with evaluations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, John S. Dickey, Fowler McCormick, Edward L. Ryerson, Frank F. Fowle, Harold Dodds, Robert G. Sproul.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 359)
    Biographies of candidates. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 360)
    Names proposed prior to meeting of April 1951. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Edgar B. Young, Robert G. Sproul, Harold Dodds.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, October-November 1951 (Box 35, Folder 361)
    Names proposed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 362)
    Biographies, arranged alphabetically. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Douglas Freeman.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1951-1952 (Box 36, Folder 363)
    Biographies and evaluations, arranged alphabetically. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Robert G. Sproul, Harold Dodds.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 364)
    Names proposed during 1952, with evaluations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William I. Myers, Harold H. Swift.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1950-1955 (Box 36, Folder 365)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1956-1959 (Box 36, Folder 366)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Candidates for Boards, 1960-1961 (Box 36, Folder 367)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 368)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Ernest M. Hopkins, Karl T. Compton, James B. Conant, Walter W. Stewart.
    30.31
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box 36, Folder 369)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Irvin Stewart, Donald B. Tresidder, Walter W. Stewart, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Ernest M. Hopkins, John S. Dickey.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Candidates, 1945-1947 (Box 36, Folder 370)
    Candidates for Rockefeller Foundation presidency. Comments on candidates. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Ernest M. Hopkins, Walter W. Stewart, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Candidates, 1946-1947 (Box 36, Folder 371)
    List of candidates, arranged by date. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Candidates (A-G), 1946-1948 (Box 37, Folder 372)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Walter W. Stewart.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Candidates (H-W), 1946-1948 (Box 37, Folder 373)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Lester B. Pearson, 1946-1947 (Box 37, Folder 374)
    Pearson's declination of presidency.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Successor to Raymond B. Fosdick - Chester Barnard, 1948-1952 (Box 37, Folder 375)
    Selected as Raymond B. Fosdick's successor.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Founders Requisitions, 1914-1917 (Box 37, Folder 376)
    Starr J. Murphy and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s requisitions upon John D. Rockefeller's reserved income form 1914 Rockefeller Foundation gift. Duplicate requisitions; index. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    30.4
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Retiring Allowances, 1919-1923 (Box 37, Folder 377)
    Committee on insurance, annuities, disability allowance and sick leave report. Devising a retirement plan. Correspondents include Edwin R. Embree, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates, Louis G. Myers.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Hecht Trust - Parents' Magazine, 1927-1943 (Box 37, Folder 378)
    Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial gift to Teacher's College, University of Iowa, University of Minnesota, and Yale, to invest in Parents' Institute. Foundation's endorsement of magazine, its success; desire of magazine to purchase "Liberty." Correspondents include Melvyn Gordon Lowenstein, Thomas M. Debevoise, Thomas B. Appleget, G. J. Hecht (President of Parents' Magazine), Arthur W. Packard.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee, 1913-1928 (Box 37, Folder 379)
    Financial situation; disposition of funds; financial policy; purchases and sales; prospects and proxies. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, Louis G. Myers, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, George E. Vincent, F. Strauss, W. Aldrich, Roger S. Greene, Edward Robinson, Barnard.
    30.5
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee, 1929-1936 (Box 37, Folder 380)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee, 1937-1961 (Box 38, Folder 381)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee - Salaries, 1919-1921 (Box 38, Folder 382)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Memoranda Regarding Rockefeller Foundation and General Education Board, 1939-1949 (Box 38, Folder 383)
    Summary figures collected by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. covering Rockefeller Foundation, General Education Board and Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee - New York Transit Company, 1940-1942 (Box 38, Folder 384)
    Merger of pipeline companies.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Finance Committee - Statements of Securities, 1957-1961 (Box 38, Folder 385)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Income - Appropriations, Account, Budget, 1909-1925 (Box 38, Folder 386)
    Lists of securities given Foundation; appropriations to unaffiliated organizations; summary statements; estimates of needs; voting of principal funds. Correspondents include George E. Vincent, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    30.6
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Income - Appropriations, Account, Budget - Letters of Authorization, 1914-1915 (Box 38, Folder 387)
    John D. Rockefeller authorizes John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Starr J. Murphy to sign requisitions.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Income - Appropriations, Account, Budget - Designations, 1915-1917 (Box 38, Folder 388)
    Record of John D. Rockefeller's designations of funds; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s decision that unused amounts should be released to Foundation at end of each year.
    30.6B
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1906-1924 (Box 38, Folder 389)
    Memos on general policy and principles, press releases, Foundation and International Health Commission; chart of Board memberships; map of activities of Foundation; diagrams of expenditures by years. Correspondents include Jerome D. Greene, Starr J. Murphy.
    30.7
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission, 1914-1919 (Box 38, Folder 390)
    Sending of Commission; policy; emergency relief; reports from Commission; regulation of activities. Expenditures to 1917. Correspondents include Wickliffe Rose, Roger S. Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    30.10
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - Belgium, 1914-1938 (Box 39, Folder 391)
    Organization; shipping problems; relations with Hoover's organization; appeals; publicity. Correspondence with Madame Vandervelde; Holland relief; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made Commandeur de l'Ordre de la Couronne and Honorary Doctor of the Faculty of Medicine of l'Universite Libre de Bruxelles. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Madame Vandervelde.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - Serbia, 1915-1916 (Box 39, Folder 392)
    Typhus epidemic; appeals. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - Poland, 1915-1919 (Box 39, Folder 393)
    Investigation; appeals; Walcott's indiscreet book on Polish investigation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wickliffe Rose, C. W. Eliot, Frederick T. Gates, F. C. Walcott.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - France - Monica Moore, 1918-1937 (Box 39, Folder 394)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s private contributions to Rockefeller Foundation nurse, Miss Moore, to help special hardship cases. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wickliffe Rose, Starr J. Murphy, George E. Vincent.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - Tuberculosis Commission in France, 1916-1932 (Box 39, Folder 395)
    Tuberculosis problem in France; cooperation with French Government and American Red Cross; administration of campaign; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. private contributions to Dr. Eversole and Mr. Gunn for relief of hardship cases; Tolstoy family hardship.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - War Relief Commission - Prisoners of War, 1916-1917 (Box 39, Folder 396)
    Plan of relief; proposed organization in conjunction with Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA). Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, W. Greene, J. R. Mott.
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Louisiana Bird Refuge, 1916-1941 (Box 39, Folder 397)
    Gift of land for refuge; tax exemption; possible State mismanagement (too much trapping). Oil possibilities; land opened to prospectors by State; Foundation transfers its reversionary rights to Department of Interior. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Thomas M. Debevoise, Raymond B. Fosdick, B. A. Harden, Starr J. Murphy, Roger S. Greene.
    30.12
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Louisiana Bird Refuge, 1942-1945 (Box 39, Folder 398)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Raymond B. Fosdick History of Foundation, 1947-1957 (Box 40, Folder 399)
    Decision to have a history of Rockefeller boards; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s suggestion that Raymond B. Fosdick write history; Raymond B. Fosdick's preparation of history. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Thomas M. Debevoise read manuscript; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. writes forward. Publication; reviews; tribute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel, Raymond B. Fosdick, W. W. Stewart, Chester Barnard, Flora M. Rhind.
    30.13
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Reports on Grants, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 400)
    First, second and third quarters.
    30.14
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, 1951-October 1952 (Box 40, Folder 401)
    Resolutions; hearings; questionnaires; committee reports. Foundation's answer to Reece Committee. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dr. Lindsley F. Kimball, Flora M. Rhind.
    30.16
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, November 1952 (Box 40, Folder 402)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, December 1952-July 1954 (Box 40, Folder 403)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, 1951-1953 (Box 40, Folder 0403A)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, August-October 1954 (Box 40, Folder 404)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Cox Resolution and Reece Investigation, November 1954-1955 (Box 40, Folder 405)
- Rockefeller Institute
  - Rockefeller Institute - Incorporation, 1900-1901 (Box 40, Folder 406)
    Background planning for Institute; search for personnel and research plans. Correspondents include Simon Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    31A
  - Rockefeller Institute - Charter and By-Laws, 1901, 1910 (Box 41, Folder 407)
    Certificate of Incorporation, 1901; Memoranda of Agreement, 1910. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Charter and By-Laws, 1910-1958 (Box 41, Folder 408)
    Changes in by-laws. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Charter and By-Laws, 1952-1953 (Box 41, Folder 0408A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Charter and By-Laws, 1908 (Box 41, Folder 409)
    Act of Amendment to Charter. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Charter and By-Laws - Correspondence, 1907-1916 (Box 41, Folder 410)
    Articles of incorporation; amendments; changes in by-laws. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Memoranda Regarding History of Institute, 1900-1911 (Box 41, Folder 411)
    Starr J. Murphy's notes and memoranda on early history of the Institute. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy.
    31B
  - Rockefeller Institute - General
    Acquisition and use of Institute property; financing; research problems; Frederick T. Gates memo to John D. Rockefeller urging support for Institute; staff research work; professional standards and ethics; anti-vivisection. World War I problems, Institute personnel's aid to war work. Expansion of Institute activities after War. Celebration of Institute's 20th anniversary; Noguchi's Paris award; hiring of personnel, choice of successor to Dr. Flexner. Publicity policy; patients; use of ground for public park. Gasser's report on Institute problems and activities. Pension plan; proposed history of Institute; gifts for research costs, bequests, awards to the Institute. Personnel problems; attempts to form an American "Academy"; alleged cures; gift of Flexner papers to Institute; grievances of patients and relatives. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Jerome D. Greene, Frederick T. Gates, Dr. Simon Flexner, Dr. E. Holt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, Waldo R. Flinn, Henry James, Edric B. Smith, Charles O. Heydt.
    31.1
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1902-1910 (Box 41, Folder 412)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1911-1913 (Box 41, Folder 413)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1914-1919 (Box 41, Folder 414)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1920-1924 (Box 42, Folder 415)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1925-1932 (Box 42, Folder 416)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1933-1934 (Box 42, Folder 417)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 418)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1937-September 1939 (Box 42, Folder 419)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, October-December 1939 (Box 42, Folder 420)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1940-1943 (Box 43, Folder 421)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1944-1948 (Box 43, Folder 422)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1949-1950 (Box 43, Folder 423)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1949-1950 (Box 43, Folder 0423A)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1951-1952 (Box 43, Folder 424)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1951-1952 (Box 43, Folder 0424A)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 425)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 0425A)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1955-1956 (Box 43, Folder 426)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1955-1956 (Box 43, Folder 0426A)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 427)
    - Rockefeller Institute - General, 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 0427A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Agreement with Navy, 1941-1945 (Box 44, Folder 428)
    Institute cooperation with Navy during World War II.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Anti-Vivisection Controversy, 1931-1957 (Box 44, Folder 429)
    Institute's reactions to anti-vivisection campaigns.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Archives Transfer, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 430)
    Transfer of Institute material to the archives and authority for destruction.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Archives Transfer, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 0430A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Blackwell Estate Legacy, 1927-1928 (Box 44, Folder 431)
    Institute's interest in small legacy.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Detlev W. Bronk, President's House, 1957-1958 (Box 44, Folder 432)
    Provision of house for President.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Detlev W. Bronk, President's House, 1958 (Box 44, Folder 0432A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Alexis Carrel, 1915-1918 (Box 44, Folder 433)
    Dr. Carrel's method of treating wounds; service in France.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Edith Cohan Will, 1924-1950 (Box 44, Folder 434)
    Legacy received by Institute.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dinner for Dr. Rufus I. Cole, 1938 (Box 44, Folder 435)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. remarks at dinner for Dr. Cole; hospital history.
  - Rockefeller Institute - New Director, 1951-1954 (Box 44, Folder 0435A)
    Selection of Dr. Detlev W. Bronk.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Garcia vs. Institute, 1918 (Box 44, Folder 436)
    Suit for malpractice.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Retirement, 1953-1957 (Box 44, Folder 437)
    Dinner, tributes, gift, proposed portrait. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Herbert S. Gasser - Report on Future Policy, 1946-1951 (Box 44, Folder 438)
    Discussion of future research directions. Correspondents include Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Frederick T. Gates Memorial Service, 1929 (Box 44, Folder 439)
    Remarks by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. William H. Welch, Simon Flexner.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Frederick T. Gates - Memorandum Regarding Future of Institute, 1908 (Box 44, Folder 440)
    Urging Rockefeller generosity toward Institute.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. L. Emmett Holt, 1915-1929 (Box 44, Folder 441)
    Recollections on beginnings of Institute by Dr. L. Emmett Holt and Frederick T. Gates.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Infantile Paralysis, 1911-1916 (Box 44, Folder 442)
    Simon Flexner's studies of infantile paralysis.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Landscaping, 1957-1958 (Box 44, Folder 443)
    David Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller gifts toward cost of landscaping grounds.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Lavoisier Portrait, 1927-1958 (Box 44, Folder 444)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of portrait to Institute; loans of portrait.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Lavoisier Portrait, 1952, 1958 (Box 44, Folder 0444A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Milk Supply, 1901-1902 (Box 45, Folder 445)
    Study of sanitary conditions in New York milk industry.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Patents, Licenses, 1936-1945 (Box 45, Folder 446)
    Institute's use of Swedish centrifuge. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Thomas B. Appleget, Edric B. Smith, Vanderbilt Webb, Chauncey Belknap, Ivan Sorvall.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Portraits for Institute, 1916-1922 (Box 45, Folder 447)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. arrangements for portraits of Institute leaders; gift of portrait of John D. Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller Institute - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Honorary Degree, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 448)
    Invitation, program; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. did not attend.
  - Rockefeller Institute - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Honorary Degree, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 0448A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Salary Adjustment, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 449)
    Increase in staff pay. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, Raymond B. Fosdick, Henry James.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Mr. Staley's Report, 1941 (Box 45, Folder 450)
    Study of business organization of Institute. Correspondents include Frank Staley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Herbert S. Gasser.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Mr. Staley's Report, 1941 (Box 45, Folder 0450A)
  - Rockefeller Institute - James B. Stokes Will, 1929-1949 (Box 45, Folder 451)
    Gifts to Institute by Stokes; annuity payments. Correspondents include James B. Stokes, Thomas M. Debevoise, Edward Robinson, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Taxes and Exemption, 1924-1961 (Box 45, Folder 452)
    New York State and Federal tax-exempt status. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Chauncey Belknap, Edric B. Smith, Edward Robinson, Waldo R. Flinn.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Model War Hospital, 1917-1919 (Box 45, Folder 453)
    Institute's model hospital for combat injuries; other wartime activities.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Winterberg Estate, 1941-1954 (Box 45, Folder 454)
    Hungarian refugee who ultimately died in Nazi concentration camp left estate to Institute; legal hassle. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Chauncey Belknap, Dr. Herbert S. Gasser, Edric B. Smith.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Winterberg Estate, 1955-1957 (Box 45, Folder 455)
    Hungarian refugee who ultimately died in Nazi concentration camp left estate to Institute; legal hassle. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Edric B. Smith, Norborne P. Gatling, Jr., Chauncey Belknap, Waldo R. Flinn, Dr. Detlev W. Bronk.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Winterberg Estate, 1954-1957 (Box 45, Folder 0455A)
    Closed material from folders 454 and 455.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Insulin - Treatment Pledge, 1923-1933 (Box 45, Folder 456)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift for allotment to hospitals to buy insulin for the poor.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Insulin - Letters of Appreciation, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 457)
  - Rockefeller Institute - Dr. Hideyo Noguchi, 1926-1938 (Box 46, Folder 458)